<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Overload</title>
    <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe" />
    <updated>2021-10-04T03:37:57+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Moe</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Moments</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/moments/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/moments/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:37:57+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    here comes the intimate moments, the fleeting moments of euphoria I could never bottle but only yearn for; and between long sighs and songs of silence, what is it we speak of? a language, a language far older than time itself, words that have never met paper, words that have never climbed out of our throats and rolled off of our tongues but bellow within the walls of our minds and, during moments of comfort and intimacy, of soft touches and flowery caresses, of the brush of fingers and gazes locked flood every inch of soul. and as it is far too overwhelming, all there is to do is sigh and enjoy such fleeting moments, a paradise commanded to root up from earth by the mere trace of fingers over skin, of warm eyes and even warmer embraces, embraces I needn’t ask for, of quiet whispers and high notes, the intimacy of immaculate songs at the earliest moments of the morning. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>here comes the intimate moments, the fleeting moments of euphoria I could never bottle but only yearn for; and between long sighs and songs of silence, what is it we speak of?  a language, a language far older than time itself, words that have never met paper, words that have never climbed out of our throats and rolled off of our tongues but bellow within the walls of our minds and, during moments of comfort and intimacy, of soft touches and flowery caresses, of the brush of fingers and gazes locked flood every inch of soul.  and as it is far too overwhelming, all there is to do is sigh and enjoy such fleeting moments, a paradise commanded to root up from earth by the mere trace of fingers over skin, of warm eyes and even warmer embraces, embraces I needn’t ask for, of quiet whispers and high notes, the intimacy of immaculate songs at the earliest moments of the morning.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Waves</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/waves/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/waves/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:37:38+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I wish I could create a symphony from the sound of waves, from the secret whispering of a pristine forest, from the twinkling of stars, from our songs and my great nostalgia. —Letters to Sofia, M.K. Ciurlionis 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I wish I could create a symphony from the sound of waves, from the secret whispering of a pristine forest, from the twinkling of stars, from our songs and my great nostalgia.
—Letters to Sofia, M.K. Ciurlionis</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Rain</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/rain/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/rain/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:37:04+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    and when you left, the stars left with you; the bodies of light you planted in the incensed skies drew back into a world I could only reach out for, my palms infinitely empty as I gaze into a space and time they now hide in, tracing my fingers over the home they painted with droplets of white glory. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>and when you left, the stars left with you; the bodies of light you planted in the incensed skies drew back into a world I could only reach out for, my palms infinitely empty as I gaze into a space and time they now hide in, tracing my fingers over the home they painted with droplets of white glory.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Religion</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/religion/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/religion/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:36:18+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    “To be a gentle mover in a swiftly spinning world. To be present. To extract the poetry. To only entertain the real. To listen to seek the genuine. To stand inside of the stretch, the momentum, the tall discomfort of change, the knowing that you don’t need to rush the practice, or ever fake or force a thing. To believe in rhythm and movement. To trust in the river, the song, the stillness, the storm, and the seed. This is my religion.” —4/7, 15:09 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>“To be a gentle mover in a swiftly spinning world. To be present. To extract the poetry. To only entertain the real. To listen to seek the genuine. To stand inside of the stretch, the momentum, the tall discomfort of change, the knowing that you don’t need to rush the practice, or ever fake or force a thing. To believe in rhythm and movement. To trust in the river, the song, the stillness, the storm, and the seed. 
This is my religion.”
—4/7, 15:09</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>I</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/i/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/i/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:35:56+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I am one of the searchers. There are, I believe, millions of us. We are not unhappy, but neither are we really content. We continue to explore life, hoping to uncover its ultimate secret. We continue to explore ourselves, hoping to understand. We like to walk along the beach, we are drawn by the ocean, taken by its power, its unceasing motion, its mystery and unspeakable beauty. We like forests and mountains, deserts and hidden rivers, and the lonely cities as well. Our sadness is as much a part of our lives as is our laughter. To share our sadness with one we love is perhaps as great a joy as we can know - unless it be to share our laughter. We searchers are ambitious only for life itself, for everything beautiful it can provide. Most of all we love and want to be loved. We want to live in a relationship that will not impede our wandering, nor prevent our search, nor lock us in prison walls; that will take us for what little we have to give. We do not want to prove ourselves to another or compete for love. For wanderers, dreamers, and lovers, for lonely men and women who dare to ask of life everything good and beautiful. It is for those who are too gentle to live among wolves. —James Kavanaugh, There Are Men Too Gentle To Live Among Wolves 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>I am one of the searchers. There are, I believe, millions of us. We are not unhappy, but neither are we really content. We continue to explore life, hoping to uncover its ultimate secret. We continue to explore ourselves, hoping to understand. We like to walk along the beach, we are drawn by the ocean, taken by its power, its unceasing motion, its mystery and unspeakable beauty. We like forests and mountains, deserts and hidden rivers, and the lonely cities as well. Our sadness is as much a part of our lives as is our laughter. To share our sadness with one we love is perhaps as great a joy as we can know - unless it be to share our laughter. 
We searchers are ambitious only for life itself, for everything beautiful it can provide. Most of all we love and want to be loved. We want to live in a relationship that will not impede our wandering, nor prevent our search, nor lock us in prison walls; that will take us for what little we have to give. We do not want to prove ourselves to another or compete for love.</p>
<p>For wanderers, dreamers, and lovers, for lonely men and women who dare to ask of life everything good and beautiful. It is for those who are too gentle to live among wolves.
—James Kavanaugh, There Are Men Too Gentle To Live Among Wolves</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Sun</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/sun/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/sun/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:35:33+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    golden globe, I weep for you. The salt inhabited pools that deprive of me clear sight are dedicated to you, as I spend countless silent nights staring at the golden rays you bestow upon that mere rock your flames ablaze for. I will not deny it, I am at fault. I preferred to have my being glistening and dripping wet in crystal light and found your lemon beams a curse, bearing an acidity that ate at my flesh until all that was left was soulless bone. I begged for the sky to be darkened and showered with those white spots of magnificence, and in the center of that breathtaking infinity, the celestial you endlessly boil harder for. mother of stars, heed my call. let my sorrows echo throughout the ever growing realm you dwell in and awaken your kin, for they too need to hear this unraveling of mine. they too need to realize that they worship who must not be totally worshipped, that they have their backs turned on she who brings forth all this beauty; it is your own embodiment that gives life to the arch of beauty that brightens up a mighty deluge, signifying the island of bliss and contentment that erupts only after a shipwreck. But it has taken a near eternity to have myself dawned in the already known truth. you are the spark that lightens up our blackened souls and perishes away the darkness, and from that burning light grew the flowers, even if not many, that encircle our concealed edges. yet you are loved by few. and yet your adoration for we underlings does not flicker. —Sun, with these words I give you my all. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>golden globe, I weep for you. The salt inhabited pools that deprive of me clear sight are dedicated to you, as I spend countless silent nights staring at the golden rays you bestow upon that mere rock your flames ablaze for. I will not deny it, I am at fault. I preferred to have my being glistening and dripping wet in crystal light and found your lemon beams a curse, bearing an acidity that ate at my flesh until all that was left was soulless bone. I begged for the sky to be darkened and showered with those white spots of magnificence, and in the center of that breathtaking infinity, the celestial you endlessly boil harder for. 
mother of stars, heed my call. let my sorrows echo throughout the ever growing realm you dwell in and awaken your kin, for they too need to hear this unraveling of mine. they too need to realize that they worship who must not be totally worshipped, that they have their backs turned on she who brings forth all this beauty; it is your own embodiment that gives life to the arch of beauty that brightens up a mighty deluge, signifying the island of bliss and contentment that erupts only after a shipwreck. But it has taken a near eternity to have myself dawned in the already known truth. you are the spark that lightens up our blackened souls and perishes away the darkness, and from that burning light grew the flowers, even if not many, that encircle our concealed edges. yet you are loved by few. and yet your adoration for we underlings does not flicker. </p>
<p>—Sun, with these words I give you my all.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Serendipity</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/serendipity/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/serendipity/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:35:05+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                     a freckled lilac sky lies awake above your head, tonight. what are stars are now flaming, white spots growing larger moment by moment, flickering in the ocean-filled eyes that stare up at them. the dandelions in the evening wind always mocked you behind your back because you could only reach so far, like a leaf bound to the branch of a tree, only free from it when October closes down on the burning heat of summer, but the passing of the comets as their thin streaks of light left traces of ethereal beauty in the velvety-blue sky melted away their scornful gazes. there’s a secret underneath those otherworldly folds. a rhythm to the beam of the moon, the shimmering of the stars and soul-stirring gleam of the northern lights. a symphony to the dance of this mass of green I lay back on, the soft whispers of the breeze and howling of the gales. the quivering of the leaves, the ebb and flow of the ocean tides. “maybe the sea carries our dreams, and we all wait for the salt to soak into our ankles, when instead, we should be out there dancing with the waves” 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p> a freckled lilac sky lies awake above your head, tonight. what are stars are now flaming, white spots growing larger moment by moment, flickering in the ocean-filled eyes that stare up at them. the dandelions in the evening wind always mocked you behind your back because you could only reach so far, like a leaf bound to the branch of a tree, only free from it when October closes down on the burning heat of summer, but the passing  of the comets as their thin streaks of light left traces of ethereal beauty in the velvety-blue sky melted away their scornful gazes.
there’s a secret underneath those otherworldly folds. a rhythm to the beam of the moon, the shimmering of the stars and soul-stirring gleam of the northern lights. a symphony to the dance of this mass of green I lay back on, the soft  whispers of the breeze and howling of the gales. the quivering of the leaves, the ebb and flow of the ocean tides.
“maybe the sea carries our dreams, and we all wait for the salt to soak into our ankles, when instead, we should be out there dancing with the waves”</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Places</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/places/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/places/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:33:56+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Take me to the cold mornings and the breath that rises, sunrises on snowy streets, to the coffee in your hands, to the paint under your fingernails from the logo on the styrofoam. To the sand covered shores and tide poles that hold the sea, to the sea that holds the moon and he starts that fall until you sleep. Take me to our shared slumber on scratchy sheets starched too stiff. Take me to the cheap hotels and take me to palaces we’ll never afford. Take me to the nights that never end, the lost and wander worn feet that collapse into bed as the sun is rising. Take me to the early evenings, tired legs sleeping sound before the sun falls below the hills. Take me our places, the creaking floors and our boots making songs stop them. The dim lit pubs and fiddle dances, the globe lights low, the hour long talks, the quiet romances. Take me down the old dirt roads, the rocks walls and clover greases. To the green and the grey to the blue and the white. Take me to our places, the stones and sticks in green hills. Take me to the rooftops made of earth. The heather and the moss and the warm rain that makes colanders of clouds and mist. Take me to the fires that burn out in the night, the embers dancing from the chimney to tangle with the stars. The green lights that flow like waves in the cold still air and the steam that rises from the tops of our heads as we stay warm in the winter. Take me to the lanterns rising into the black, wishes carried on flame and fabric, prayers to all the gods we have never seen. Take me to those high white peaks, to the colored flags climbing center poles and the breathless air we struggle to breathe. To the mantra painted rocks filling freezing streams the gentle hands weathered old. Take me to the swaying trains, the hands on the walls to keep our balance. the sleeper cars and sliding doors, the crumpled maps in reclined seat backs. —tyler knott gregson 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Take me to the cold mornings and the breath that rises, sunrises on snowy streets, to the coffee in your hands, to the paint under your fingernails from the logo on the styrofoam. To the sand covered shores and tide poles that hold the sea, to the sea that holds the moon and he starts that fall until you sleep. Take me to our shared slumber on scratchy sheets starched too stiff. Take me to the cheap hotels and take me to palaces we’ll never afford. Take me to the nights that never end, the lost and wander worn feet that collapse into bed as the sun is rising. Take me to the early evenings, tired legs sleeping sound before the sun falls below the hills. Take me our places, the creaking floors and our boots making songs stop them. The dim lit pubs and fiddle dances, the globe lights low, the hour long talks, the quiet romances. Take me down the old dirt roads, the rocks walls and clover greases. To the green and the grey to the blue and  the white. 
Take me to our places, the stones and sticks in green hills. Take me to the rooftops made of earth. The heather and the moss and the warm rain that makes colanders of clouds and mist. Take me to the fires that burn out in the night, the embers dancing from the chimney to tangle with the stars. The green lights that flow like waves in the cold still air and the steam that rises from the tops of our heads as we stay warm in the winter. Take me to the lanterns rising into the black, wishes carried on flame and fabric, prayers to all the gods we have never seen. Take me to those high white peaks, to the colored flags climbing center poles and the breathless air we struggle to breathe. To the mantra painted rocks filling freezing streams the gentle hands weathered old. Take me to the swaying trains, the hands on the walls to keep our balance. the sleeper cars and sliding doors, the crumpled maps in reclined seat backs.
—tyler knott gregson</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Quest</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/quest/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/quest/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:33:08+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    It seems I lost myself Somewhere I’ve never been before, That my pieces kiss the sand Upon some unknown distant shore. I hear them softly falling For the chance to reunite, If home is where the heart is Then I have no home in sight. I know not where to find them, In which direction I shall start, Only that life appears a quest; An endless search for every part, And that the longer I stand still The more I surely slip away, So I must leave out of the fear Of what may happen if I stay —e.h. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>It seems I lost myself 
Somewhere I’ve never been before, 
That my pieces kiss the sand 
Upon some unknown distant shore. 
I hear them softly falling 
For the chance to reunite, 
If home is where the heart is 
Then I have no home in sight. 
I know not where to find them, 
In which direction I shall start, 
Only that life appears a quest; 
An endless search for every part, 
And that the longer I stand still 
The more I surely slip away, 
So I must leave out of the fear 
Of what may happen if I stay 
—e.h.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dark</title>
        <author>
            <name>Moe</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/dark/"/>
        <id>https://criticalinsight.github.io/moe/dark/</id>

        <updated>2021-10-04T03:32:40+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    They drove for hours to the ocean, Just for the proof that they had been, Then watched the sunset’s splendid colors, Through the pixels of a screen, Left before the sky had darkened, And the night had learnt their names, With their fingers tapping light, That would have put the moon’s to shame, Ten billion stars all tried to stop them, To beg that they should see more, Instead of sleeping in hotels, That boast the fact that they have four, But their only constellations, Were the cracks across their ceiling, As they sent their one-word answers, As a substitute for feelings, And with the traffic as a soundtrack, They soon drifted off to sleep, And didn’t even slightly stir, When all the clouds began to weep —e.h. 
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>They drove for hours to the ocean,
Just for the proof that they had been,
Then watched the sunset’s splendid colors,
Through the pixels of a screen,
Left before the sky had darkened,
And the night had learnt their names,
With their fingers tapping light, 
That would have put the moon’s to shame, 
Ten billion stars all tried to stop them, 
To beg that they should see more, 
Instead of sleeping in hotels, 
That boast the fact that they have four, 
But their only constellations, 
Were the cracks across their ceiling, 
As they sent their one-word answers, 
As a substitute for feelings, 
And with the traffic as a soundtrack, 
They soon drifted off to sleep, 
And didn’t even slightly stir, 
When all the clouds began to weep
—e.h.</p>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
